CATHERINE PHAM

Seattle, Washington, USA +1-734-931-6036 crypticwoodwhite@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://crypticwoodwhite.github.io/ Github: https://github.com/CrypticWoodWhite LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/catherinephamcww

Junior full-stack web developer with ten years of experience in wildlife biology research. Currently learning both front- and back-end technologies at the University of Washington Coding Boot Camp. Strong analytical skills, attention to detail, and both independent and capable of working well with people from a variety of backgrounds.

PROJECTS

Rain on Your Parade

https://stefan-apr.github.io/Rain-on-Your-Parade/

- Collaboratively developed an app that allows users to search events and see the weather forecast for those events.
- Responsible for the weather forecast portion of the app, and contributed to the front-end design.
- Technologies used: HTML/CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Firebase, four APIs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web development: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Node.js, Bootstrap, MySQL, Firebase, Git

Data analysis: R, SAS, ArcGIS

Database management: MySQL, MS Access, Act!

SELECTED EXPERIENCE

Ardenna Ecological Research, Seattle, WA

2011 - Present

Wildlife Biologist

- Provide a variety of ecological research services to government agencies and academic institutions in order to further their research, conservation, and management goals.
- Specialized in the fields of wildlife biology, seabird ecology, marine ecology, and fisheries management.

Hawai'i Pacific University, Kaneohe, HI

2014 - 2016

Teaching Assistant

- Assisted in teaching five classes with up to 30 students in HPU's College of Natural and Computational Sciences.
- Four of those classes were lecture-based, and three of those classes had both undergraduate and graduate students.

Ocean Trawler Yachts, Seattle, WA

CRM Database Manager

2013 - 2014

• Successfully oversaw the transition of over twenty years of paper records into the customer relationship management database *Act!*, and trained staff in the use of the database.

Northwest Seaport, Seattle, WA

2013 - 2014

Volunteer

• Built a new volunteer, donor, and donation database in MS Access for a non-profit to replace a poorly designed database and several MS Excel documents so as to more efficiently and securely manage information.

EDUCATION

University of Washington, Coding Boot Camp	2019
Hawai`i Pacific University, M.S. Marine Science	2016
University of Virginia, B.S. Environmental Sciences	2009